everybody we are back it is the second
episode of Jack Murphy live podcast and
I am joined here today by will
Chamberlain mr. periscope will how are
you doing today doing fantastic will is
a lawyer and a political commentator and
he has been keeping us all up to date on
a number of issues that have been
happening most notably in the recent
past the Cavanaugh hearings and
everything leading up to that will was
on the ball on the spot with that and
had great success with his periscopes
everything went well yeah gained a lot
of followers got a lot of traction I
mean that's that's the measure of
success on Twitter and periscope I think
certainly as plus you're getting the
good word out there and I think that you
got a lot of traction with that so
that's been exciting and then here to my
left because we're sitting at my dining
room table
at Jack Murphy live worldwide
headquarters in Washington DC yeah she's
shaking her head at me I have the lovely
redhead and we're gonna just keep
calling her the redhead this whole time
because that's her pen name and that's
her name sure yeah I mean totally okay
with that you're totally okay with and
she and we'll both are going to be sort
of like rotating regular co-hosts mostly
because they live in Washington DC I'm
friends with them but no but really
because both of them have great
perspective to bring to the various
conversations that we're having and on
the podcast here you know we're gonna
have a whole slew of experts and people
who knows things about a lot of
different things I said that really well
for a professional word guy come by and
talk about on a whole different range of
topics and so sometimes we're gonna talk
about sex and relationships and be
always nice to have a female perspective
on that sometimes we're going to talk
about politics and culture and that's
why I've got will here he's the expert
sometimes we're just gonna talk about
whatever and we're both all three of us
are experts on that perfect I'm very
good at whatever you're very good at
whatever happens to be a special team
recently the redhead and I just came
back from the University of New Mexico
but actually not even the University of
Mexico because I got man before I got
there we never made it we never made it
so as part of my fall 2018 Democrat to
the pourable book
to her I was scheduled to speak at the
University of New Mexico at the law
school a faculty member there reached
out to me and invited me directly like
in the other instances with the College
Republicans and stuff I've been reaching
out to them and setting up these these
dates but the University of New Mexico
law school reached out to me directly
and paid for both of our flights paid
for our hotel asked us to come out there
and give a talk but the day before the
day before I left the night before the
night before we were like bags packed
everything was by the door we were like
getting ready to go to bed early because
we had a flight the next morning and we
get a call saying hey guess what you're
cancelled you're banned Jack Murphy too
dangerous
no well you can't roll your eyes on
podcasting you have to say stuff and so
the lady in New Mexico she told me that
she had met with the head of the law
school and then she had met with
security there and they were told that
there was like gonna be a security
threats some sort of danger or risk to
the people who may be attending my talks
which is crazy isn't well like I'm not
we know people that are far more
outrageous and provocative than I am
right I mean part of how the lift
operates I guess now is that they just
come out they threaten you and that's
how they bully these administration's
which probably didn't want to host you
in the beginning from hosting you they
give you they create a pretext right
because if you know if a popular
left-wing speaker was coming to speak at
the at the University of New Mexico law
school and some right winger came out
and threatened them do you really think
that New Mexico would ban that speaker
no odds are extremely low right no they
would just tell that protester just to
go home and be quiet about it because
hey free speech right so we would go out
there anyway right the head of security
says no the head of the law school says
no they canceled the event one day
before and they cite because it was like
the day before midterm elections and
they cite oh it's too dangerous to have
these conversations right before midterm
elections does that right that sounds
like I'm in America
I know it sounds like you're you're
engaging an election meddling Jack
sounds like we need a special counsel
investigation just for you right exactly
I know you know the truth is is that I
think that my subject matter isn't
really that provocative definitely
definitely not what's in the book
Democrat to the pleura ball I mean it
doesn't seem provocative to me but maybe
some of the older stuff you know what
happens they start googling right and
there are hit pieces out there on me
that just won't go away the search
engine optimization is pretty good and
they've got a good platform power so
people will start googling and then all
of a sudden it's like oh this guy can't
come and then free speech is in jeopardy
and that's that but the Google problem
is one that essentially it's like it's
part of it's part of the broader warfare
right it only works because the left has
so much dominant cultural power I was
thinking about this the other day we're
really just this morning that you know
people who support Trump and support the
president they're the people who are
vulnerable to being deep platformed
people who oppose the president are not
vulnerable to being deep platformed now
in a world where Republicans were as
powerful as left often to thinks of them
as right they say oh you know the
Republicans had they have Congress they
have the executive branch they have so
much power there into the courts we
don't have that sort of same cultural
power at all like nothing resembling it
and so people who support the government
of the United States are at risk of DMD
platform people who oppose it are
lionized it's a it's a very it's a weird
power asymmetry and it also made me
think that if the right actually had
cultural power and the way that the left
does the left would never win an
election again ever ever ever right like
well and they they act like the exact
opposite is true right right like
Republicans and people that that support
Donald Trump have this cultural power
they have this influence or they have
the money or they're the leaves or
they're dominant or or whatever the case
may be but the truth is is that from
universities professional organizations
institutions media institutions
entertainment marketing advertising all
the way up and down the entire spectrum
of American culture the left is in
charge and the Liberals are running
things right and the left has to look at
it differently because part of their
entire narrative is David versus Goliath
they're they're self-justifying
narrative of why they're the story they
tell themselves is that they are
fighting either repressed themselves
we're fighting on behalf of oppressed
populations against the powerful but you
actually look if you think hard about
who actually has power elite there was
no money for Trump and there really
wasn't a lot of money for Republican
candidates this cycle there was tons of
money for Democratic candidates and the
realignment that occurred in the wake of
2016 moved a lot of delete coastal
Republicans to Democrats to the
Democratic side and the trade-off is
that we now have a chance of a fighting
chance of winning the Rust Belt and a
fighting chance of winning the
presidency but the downside is we have a
lot less money to do it with than we
used to us are as like a Republican
Party and it also means that cultural
power is much more consolidated with the
Democrats because they not only have the
cultural power that comes from Hollywood
in academia David they now have the
additional cultural power of all the
sort of elite Republicans their money
and their periodicals things like the
Weekly Standard and you know all the
people who were on CNN and being really
annoying
well one thing that it struck me in this
less of the midterms with the Texas
campaign for Senate
apparently some unheard of amount of
money out of state money flowed into
Texas to try to influence the Senate the
Senate campaign right and I started to
think when we're talking about this idea
of Russian influence and outside
meddling on the national politicking
scene how is that not analogous to
outside money from us outside of a state
flowing into a state to try to sway
voters by people who don't live they
live in that state and who don't vote in
that state and our domiciled in that
state there it's like literal actual out
of jurisdiction metal
in an election I'm sure and mean as well
as the media's decision to just drown
everybody in coverage of beta or orc and
ignore his flaws which are pretty
profound I mean the dude had a DUI and
not just any DUI like a DUI and hit run
you know in his late 20s I think is the
the time period that's not that long ago
you know that for him for him he's a
younger guy and then you had people like
John James in Michigan right John James
young black entrepreneur Air Force pilot
nearly you know fighting hard getting a
lot of votes doing pretty well you know
in a rough cycle for Republicans into a
state that's generally been pretty
democratic you cently you know we lost
by like five zero coverage from the
mainstream media and that's what that
gives you and and so from my perspective
like you getting D platformed
at New Mexico and it's part of the
broader theme of conservatives finding
themselves D platformed in academia is
part of the broader theme of the media
covering Democrats and Republicans
completely differently which is all a
part of this broad cultural power the
Democrats can bring to bear and that
Republicans currently can't well and
what strikes me as being particularly
nefarious is that I'm actually out here
trying to build bridges like I'm trying
to help people understand how you can
have a political realignment or a
culture awakening but also trying to use
the language and the ideas from both
sides to try to bring people together
can't do that that's still a fad right I
think that's you buddy if you bring
everyone together then there's no
victims there's no oppressor
they have no mission right so I'm out
here building bridges and people are
trying to tear me down and that should
tell you a lot about where we are
in this our current
today no we're not we're not unified
it's possible in the next two years we
will be because maybe Pelosi and trumps
start working together like oddly enough
I after Pelosi speech in the aftermath
of the midterms I was like I hope she's
speaker because she's making noises like
she actually wants to get things done
which would be unbelievably good for the
overall social climate right if
Democrats in Congress work together with
Republicans in the Senate and Trump and
actually passed a few pieces of
legislation that would be a huge that
would be amazing
temperature reducing moment yeah which
is exactly why I can't imagine anything
like that ever really happening I mean
that you could you could Trump could say
I will sign whatever Democratic fantasy
bill that you want I just want the
Democrats to love me I'll do whatever
you want and a whole wide world close he
just put it on my desk and they still
wouldn't vote anything across the table
if they knew that I had Trump support
that's that's my my take on it I mean I
would love to see like an actual
infrastructure spending like if you're
gonna spend money let's invest it in the
United States on things that we're all
gonna reap the benefit of we're gonna
put people to work we're gonna buy us
steel and concrete and all kinds of
great stuff but I just I can't see that
happening cuz how could they possibly
give him a victory how could they give
Trump a victory no they can't I mean
their that's the problem with you know
politics based on resistance it's like
you have to resist and that means you
don't let waving the Trump you get
credit for pass it'll be bad for the
brand too for all those Democrats
because to say it's like a brand how
could they work with him those traders
they don't really represent us right
well I'm out here trying to build
bridges man people are tearing me down
but the the tour continues
in fact this I guess I'll probably air
this after afterwards when I'm going to
Rutgers tomorrow night on the 13th
mm-hmm driving up to New Jersey to speak
to some college Republicans and then
after that we've got Evergreen State
College coming up well there's some
questions about my talk at Columbia
University but we're gonna get into that
a little bit later as the time
approaches but I'm definitely going to
have a green snake college still awesome
that should be awesome fun that should
be a good barometer an enemy territory
right oh yeah right behind behind enemy
lines the Vipers pit pit of vipers mmm
yeah I'm not sure how that goes I just
think of Ragnar every time you say that
oh right because Ragnar got just makes
me sad he got murdered by by like being
thrown into a pit of snakes literal pit
filled with vipers right that didn't
look like the best way to go no but it's
good for your mythology don't I yeah I
love Ragnar Vikings is coming can't wait
for that
Vikings coming ok so here are some of
the topics that we're gonna try to get
to today we're gonna get to nationalism
versus globalism and patriotism where
that all fits in there and what sort of
is there such a thing as nationalism or
libertarian nationalists that's
something that I've been thinking quite
a lot a lot about actually I went to
George Mason for economics undergrad so
I'm pretty well steeped in libertarian
market-based thinking but I've been
toying with this idea like how what if
do these values end at a border and our
borders real or abstract and should they
impact the the way that markets work and
the way your morality is applied to
other human beings so we're gonna get to
that but the first thing I want to talk
about is this this nationalism versus
global or something that's in the news
right now so why don't you sort of get
us all up to speed and describe what's
been what's been happening so I think it
was either yesterday or the day before
probably yesterday where Emmanuel macron
the Prime Minister of France got up and
said that nationalism was treason that
it was the opposite of patriotism and he
said that while Trump was sitting right
there at the audience and Trump had
famously declared himself to be a
nationalist about three weeks ago at a
rally and this this criticism of
nationalism feeds off of some of the
American criticisms people like Bill
Kristol but a whole bunch of
progressives as well caitlin collins and
CNN famously saying nationalism is
hitler why would you want to be hitler
like as erudite is that same and so you
have she made that she made a hitler
reference you made another reference
twenty-six-year-old you know journalism
graduate gets up and says why is he
calling himself a nationalism this is
what nationalism means it's like no
you're 26 you don't know a national
you just don't we should elect her to
Congress yeah no I mean funny thing is I
actually think we can get that's another
interesting saga conversation the
Republicans are completely messing up
with Alexandria Ocasio Cortez and she's
gonna be a star messing up how how by
like trying to hit her for being poor
basically and like not being super smart
about it before being able to afford
things I had a really good tweet about
that yeah I I tweeted a what person what
kind of person wakes up in the morning
it says you know who we need making laws
in America 20-something chicks that
can't afford an apartment without a
government job now I thought twice about
sending that sweet and you know it's
always the ones where you're like maybe
I shouldn't send this one that do really
well it's true yeah that one that one
blew up but you know it's it's a joke I
don't mean a hundred percent literally
but at the same time you know it's it's
interesting to think how many people do
you run into in their 20s at all male or
female rich or poor that you would feel
comfortable making laws to apply to the
population in general so I'm oh I wasn't
making a sexist comment or even a
class's comment it was really a just
because I'm really an ageist and that's
fair most of the time I find myself
pretty frustrated by like kids in their
early 20s because I know what I thought
in my early 20s it's totally different
from what I think today ten years later
right it was really stupid right and but
with much more competence oh yeah I was
super confident that I had figured out
role politics just completely figured it
out I like anybody just listened to the
right like we should have ceased heads
in the middle of the ocean to compete
with governments so that they can so
that they can put competitive pressure
on existing governments to serve their
citizens better I genuinely thought that
was like the solution to politics that's
so simple you guys you mean just like
living on an abandoned oil platform yeah
somebody actually did that there's all
sorts of stuff like there's some Duty
seal and ICAO and seal and was on this
abandoned oil platform somewhere in the
North Atlantic
they put a data haven there it's like
this hyper libertarianism basically ya
know it's not a terrible idea we can get
we can get back to the congresswoman and
we can get back to the young lady on CNN
calling calling Trump oh my god
not see that was really original you
actually sat around at night trying to
come up with you know a negative term
because the products about three weeks
long creative processes is what that it
okay so we're talking about nationalism
and Trump's definition naturalism and
and Mark Marcone of France is is saying
that basically Trump is Hitler - it's
what he said effectively which is really
just one disrespectful from a head of
state especially at the head of a vassal
state of the United States thing I sorry
you don't you don't get to be an
independent country if you are dependent
on another country's military umbrella
and to be disrespectful as a leader
right to his face and is quite something
and what kind of what event what event
was essentially this is that the I think
the World War one Armistice Day event in
France it was actually in a moment where
they're honoring American what are they
honoring American contribution to the
ending World War all so is that a
politically tone-deaf on mark Holmes
part or is that calculated know I'm a
little of both I think it he's already
hurting very badly in the polls in in
France like his pull his approvals just
by getting go from an very firm anywhere
from like twenty to thirty percent for
an approval rating which is shocking
compared to you know Trump has like a
forty four percent approval rating not
have you talked to rasp right now me I'm
all the way up about fifty but no I mean
Frank
Mike Romo is not popular but he's
popular among people I would refer to as
globalists and what's your working
definition of goals lobo lists is is a
person who I believe prioritizes the
interests of humanity about the
interests of their own nation right and
by their by nation I mean aligned with
the nation state so you know if I'm an
American nationalists effort to
prioritize America the interests of the
American nation American citizens over
the interests of people of other
countries and the thing about it is you
ask most people in those citizens of
their own countries do they want their
leaders to prioritize their interests or
the interests of people from other
countries they'll say I want you to
prioritize my interests moreover you
know many of the commitments made by
people who consider themselves
kind of these global citizen types
they're committed to things like
universal health care in their own
countries it's extremely hard to justify
universal health care in your own
country if you don't believe that you
should prioritize the interests of your
own citizens above those of other
countries universal health care is
really expensive and it's a benefit that
goes solely to your own citizens that's
money that could get more bang for the
buck in terms of improving health
outcomes in Africa or Southeast Asia or
any number of other places and you don't
spend it there you spend it on your own
citizens why because at a certain point
we all kind of intuitively understand
that it's moral to prioritize the
interests of your community above other
communities right and so when that
community extends to the nation state
you know it's like people who prioritize
the interests of far away people and
don't care about their own family we
immediately think of that as like a
soulish yeah you know and just something
immoral and unethical we have to help
yourself in order to be able to help
other people right you know I mean you
have to be in a position of strength in
order to help others right but there's
also just a sort of like why don't you
care about your own family you know okay
even on a basic level I know you've
probably had this experience I've had it
with you know personal issues to my own
family where I've had very close
relations kind of distanced themselves
from me as a result of just being
involved in right-wing politics and I in
my Mirren's other people have like found
this appalling mhm and it's like why do
we find that so intuitively appalling
because well obviously you're supposed
to care most about your family they're
most about you know that's that's blood
that's your core the people you're
supposed to care so presumably these
globalists have their own tribe right
their own family that they're presuming
to care about who's that I mean I think
they I'm not sure I mean they're sort of
the difference between their explicit
remarks and their implicit behavior
right so the explicit remarks are their
family there isn't they're not caring
more about the citizens and non-citizens
right there but they are very very
deeply caring about the rights of the
other and that's part of signaling about
their is that's a way of signaling
virtue implicitly they end up caring
most about the people who agree with
them politically right and so that ends
up being the core in-group that they
truly defend and hold to a different
standard than everybody else right so
it's like are there
financial interest power interest
control things like that that bind those
people together and it's out why no I
I'm not I don't think it's nearly that
pragmatic or or sort of like hard-headed
because I don't think that's why people
like why the left kind of stays together
in that way they're not there's not some
cynical underlying blood for you know
kind of like we want the money we want
the oil motivation I I genuinely think
these people are you know how about what
they definitely see as a higher
motivation than that which is you know
looking out for the good of humanity
looking up for the good of the
environment looking out for the other
and the oppressed and then if you're a
person who signals properly that you do
those things then you end up being part
of the in-group that does effectively
get treated that way because I guess
another point to be made is that there's
always going to be some sort of in-group
whose interests you prioritize over the
broader population like even as a one
humanity liberal in effect in the way
you behave you're gonna you're gonna
essentially treat your closer relations
to a different standard well and excuse
me where does that come from I mean
that's that's because we're tribal
tribal and animals that are used to
living in small groups right and here we
are now interfacing you know instead of
with 30 to 50 people we're interfacing
with like seven billion people right and
so it's good natural tendency to find
you find your own tribe and find your
own group and you have your own end
group and I think that's a natural
instinct that plays itself out on the
political spectrum on all sides it's
just that I guess in this question it's
you know is your in-group gonna be the
people that live next door to you or is
your in-group couldn't be people that
are living on the other side of the
planet right and then I mean it
shouldn't be the people who live on the
other side of the planet and I think
that it's just it's not moral to have
your to ignore those closest to you and
then and then it's probably like think
all the time that your moral because you
care about the interests of those in
sub-saharan Africa I just don't it's not
saying that you shouldn't care about
people in southern certain it's here in
Africa yeah I think if you should but
it's like having concentric circles of
caring in these as they expand outward
they be those bonds become less strong
right well and you know that that's sort
of my model for self-improvement and
development to which is take care of
yourself first that's your number one
priority
take care of your body take care of your
mind get enough sleep get enough food
get enough to eat and it's not because
of a selfish reason we're like I love
myself the most so I'm gonna take care
of myself that way no it's so that you
can be a better utility to the people
who are around you so you can be a
better and higher greater used to your
media family and then if you get that
taken care of then your community a
little bit broader maybe your nation
maybe the world but if you spend your
time worrying about the nation and the
world first then your internal you know
yourself your individual self is going
to suffer for it and I think that's sort
of where the nationalism globalism
debate is really falling right now is is
it possible to be concerned with the
welfare of people outside of your
in-group outside of your nation-state as
a priority and then still maintain the
independent inherent value and strength
of yourself as individual or your
nation-state as an individual and to me
it's insane that this is even like a
real question how do you how do you
think that this idea of taking care of
your your own citizens with your own
national interests first how did that
become a pejorative and where where and
when do you know I mean maybe we'd none
of us know but how did this how did this
really happen so I think it's a
combination of two big sort of one big
historical event and then one big
academic intellectual trend right so
first the historical event is world war
ii which while people like you are
Mazzoni who's a really really good
thinker on nationalism he he he views
germans ideology as imperialistic right
it wasn't nationalists in the sense of
respecting individual nation states it
was imperialistic it was trying to
impose a german empire german dominion
over other states which is and he draws
that distinction i do too
but the way that the general world
treated world war ii is an outbreak of
is an outbreak of nationalism it's just
too much and that we need to shut it
down oddly enough replacing it with like
this european union which is yet another
sort of distinct but in another
imperialist idea
a liberal imperialist idea instead of a
racist imperialism yeah but ultimately
still imperialist mm-hmm so that's one
trend the sort of World War two making
national is on a dirty word because
that's what the intellectuals associated
with Hitler was strong with others and
then the second is the ultimate
resurgence of I think Marxism on the
left in academia because underlying
Marxism especially classical Marxism is
the idea that classes cross national you
know internationally will unify to
revolt against higher classes workers of
the world unite
right and so so there's a natural
tendency to very find the nationalistic
impulse somewhat reactionary somewhat
like retrograde so you know it's
interesting to see some of the the more
sophisticated Marxist thinkers a guy
like Benedict Anderson who wrote a book
called imagined communities when they
come to actually grapple with
nationalism because they've had these
situations where two Marxist countries
invaded one another right go into
Southeast Asia in the 70s and 80s you
had like Vietnam and Cambodia attacking
each other in wars they're both these
are both Marxist nations and good
standing among the International
communist movement but they're attacking
each other due to these strong
nationalistic impulses so they've had to
grapple with it in their own way but
overall I think the fact that academia
leads so leftwards is this really force
against nationalism because if you're
Pro this kind of you know one world
humanity Pro Cholet area and the
classical sense or just Pro the
unification of marginalized oppressed
peoples nationalism doesn't really fit
into that matrix at all right and the
people that were in charge of and
running nationalistic countries also
tended to be the property owners and the
entrepreneurs and the people of power
and the landed people and so you know
that is the natural enemy to Marxism
obviously you know it all starts with
property rights and you know
that's a interestingly enough if you
take a very specific approach to
nationalism it's really about defending
defending personal property rights kind
of I mean it's it's something more than
that right like what is so this helps to
understand like what is a nation right
like what is so a nation is an imagined
community right that's the key line out
of Benedict Anderson the idea is that we
don't know all 300 million people in the
United States but we like collectively
conceptualize ourselves as part of a
nation with them it's in a mat it's and
we all jointly have this imagination
together again by saying it's imaginary
that doesn't mean it's not real in the
sense that it's just not tangible it's
just not tangible exactly yeah this is a
key point that was made in the sapiens
book as well yeah right yeah I remember
reading sapiens and he made the exact
same argument I'm pretty sure he also
ready anderson himself right being able
to organize around an imaginary concept
right but what what roots that imaginary
can't do you know concept and makes it
things that people go out and fight and
die for you know culture language
history shared myths shared values all
those things are really tangible to
people it's you know we we joke about
you know we for one thing that we do on
Twitter we fly the flag right I have a
flag and my name is bio we put flags
when it's close to election time the
reason we do that is because the flag is
arson this incredibly powerful symbol
that makes people more think more about
their nation and more conservative so we
we want people in the up run up to
election to see flags lots of them lots
of American flags it has it's an
incredibly powerful motivating force for
people you know motivates people to
fight and die it's motivated them to
fight and die for hundreds of years this
national identity protection of the
nation as opposed to merely their tribe
and so that isn't that isn't really
going anywhere the question is do you
harness that and do you use you'd like
ramp up the positive benefits of it or
do you try and squelch it and I feel
like the left and micron and all these
people are like nationalism is this evil
dirty thing we need to try and squelch
it's like well one it's not and you're
slandering your own countrymen and
countrywomen by doing that
but to you can't you can't squelch it if
you try and squelch it you'll lose
because you don't prioritize the
interests of the people that everybody
else thinks he probably should be
prioritizing I think what's interesting
is that if you put it in a historical
perspective nationalism is a fairly
recent concept right I mean even the
nation-state itself well exactly and you
know the American Revolution in the
French Revolution 18th century is really
the first manifestation of any type of
nationalism and I think many people
would see that as a positive right and
then it grew it grew and like in Europe
the 19th century is considered to be the
Europe the peak of European nationalism
that is something that defines the 19th
century in Europe and then you know the
beginning of the 20th century the United
States super nationalism were closed off
we're not participating we're caring
about America and now we're
transitioning all the way to the other
side we're now nationalism is in its
other extreme right so now it's
globalism it's not nationalism and we're
having these conversations about what is
it you know because it's such a recent
concept essentially if you think about
human history right of human history I
mean think about how long people have
discussed you know what is democracy now
we're talking about what is nationalism
and if you could do away with
nationalism what is left because before
nationalism it was divided into like all
the Christians were together and then
there's this Muslim world and then you
know we've divided ourselves into tribes
always and so the way we've organized
the world now is based on nations and so
if we get rid of that concept what is
the world I mean the one extreme would
be like it's going to dissolve something
else has to bind assault I still can't I
still can't get past this question of
you know if Donald Trump hadn't said
that he was a nationalist what Marcone
be saying nationalism is bad no no
probably not no right and so how much of
this sort of anti nationalistic I'm
making air quotes that you guys can't
see how much of this anti nationalistic
rhetoric is just politically motivated
out of spite and anger and fear and
hatred of Donald Trump and legitimately
you know a legitimate critique of like
of nationalism I mean what's your take
there I think it's like 90% you know tea
Trump animus oh yeah actually trying to
assign the Trump just makes people angry
so when Trump's associates himself with
an idea you can be uncharitable to that
idea people do it absolutely so I think
it has to be I mean maybe there's 10% a
legitimate critique of nationalism and
and I'm sure people like Bill Kristol on
the weekly stay but what does what those
critiques be like talking talk that
through because you know on this podcast
I don't want anybody to ever accuse us
of just being you know one-sided and
just hammering things homeless we want
to talk about it from both sides I mean
are there legitimate critiques of a
nationalistic perspective well when the
nation takes priority over the
individual to an extreme right so
anything in extreme
so--that's but that sounds like fascism
exactly right so that's like it morphs
right when you go into the extreme if
you prioritize the nation and the air
quotes the good of the nation right over
the individual and they end up
sacrificing the individual rather than
lifting up all individuals right it can
also be too much prioritization of of
national interest and in disregard of
the rights and in terms of City you know
foreign people right non-citizens so if
you know you get to the point where
you're purely national interest focused
then maybe you think it's in your
national interest to conquer a country
and subject subjugate them right right
now you can again hezonia would make the
argument that once you start doing that
you're you're outside of nationalism as
a foreign policy question because
nationalism is a foreign policy theory
is one that respects individual nation
state sovereignty and one thinks that
the ideal world is one where you have
plenty of individual nation states
pursuing their own objectives but is the
idea sort of that in the same way that a
libertarian would expect that two
individuals would make unique decisions
with themselves as the priority and then
when all the unique individuals come
together that their decision-making will
optimize outcome for the society at
large is that sort of the same thinking
when it comes to nation states being
individual units that are
self-preservation self-preserving
self-motivated but then also trying to
find
way to work sort of together
collectively in a global environment
yeah there's a little I think there's a
little bit of that in terms of like
there's a little bit of idealized
thinking about what happens when nations
are individually pursuing their own
interests does that necessarily lead to
good things right like that's the sort
of no actually the you know the world is
a state of anarchy and if you have all
these individual nation states better
actually competing for power then you
get you know world wars you get right
because on an individual level with
humans and inside your markets and
you're in your country you're
constrained by you can straight by the
law right
you know nation states aren't
necessarily I mean sure there's
international orders and international
trade agreements and you know the UN and
whatever but really at the end of the
day like there's not really
international law constraining people
from doing things if they wanted to go
out there and invade the country next
door to them they're just gonna do it
when is that ever been sanctioned I
guess the UN does a little bit of that
but really you know the UN's acting
basically like as the u.s. is sort of
surrogate in that regard when it's I
mean the u.s. is maintaining the global
World Order and in many ways we are
actually a functional Empire even though
I'm anti imperialist in that sense we're
a functional environ T the safety of the
world shipping lanes we have the biggest
military in the world and we are the
people who make you know essentially
operate kind of as a world's policeman
telling people like don't invade right
like we are the big either you're not
gonna mess with us and we that is
against our interests so don't do it are
you familiar with this independent
journalist as a Caitlyn Johnstone yeah
yeah she's been writing a lot lately
about how the US military is like the
worst thing that ever happened to the
planet Earth and that we need to pull
back immediately exclusively with the
exclusive goal of just defending our
borders and that's the only thing that
the US military should be used for and I
tried to try to talk to her she's like
well no one has been trying to invade
the United States forever why do we need
to be force projecting all over the
country and no this is like a woman that
gets pretty good traction right she's
got now since Allen's readers and she's
pretty well regarded
I tried to remind her a one by force
projection other people aren't
projecting their force right so that's
the absence of an invading army is not
going it's not a guarantee that there
won't be invading armies it's just a
testament to the strength of the
military but be I brought up this very
same question about the shipping lanes
like we have other interests like
nations and this is a really interesting
question between nationalism and
globalism nation-states defend their
interests right not just necessarily
their borders right right and it's in
our interest to have the shipping lanes
open all around the world and it's our
interest to have certain things be
stable and under our Dominion and
whatnot that's not necessarily about
Empire and it's not necessarily about
globalism but specifically about our
national interests and to what extent is
that conversation being had in this
globalists versus nationalist debate
well I think you know that almost isn't
really I wouldn't say necessarily fits
on the either side of it it's kind of
more Liberty it's kind of both
libertarianism and left libertarianism
which devolves to this like pacifism
almost isolationism I don't want to be
too unfair to you know the Rand Paul
types but like there's that little
strain of that that's just like we
should just not do any of this stuff
period right it's wrong we shouldn't be
in any wars period we shouldn't have a
military overseas period they shouldn't
be stationed in South Korea say right
you know that's that's like South Korea
just as a quick side notice is one of
those things that I really flipped my
mind on you know I would think when I
was a libertarian I was like why are we
why do we have 50,000 troops in South
Korea and then once I became a
conservator I was like because that way
it's North Korea knows that if they drop
a bomb unsold that the United States has
populated that we are not going anywhere
that we will have lost a huge number of
men and that we will you know we will
retaliate with overwhelming force rape
are committed is a as a term borrowed
from poker which means that you've got
enough money in the pot relative to in
your stack that you have to keep going
in the hand you have no choice no no
rational choice but to move forward
right so that's what so that serves to
deter North Korea from doing anything
silly and that's that is one of our
foreign policy
trysts right it's not in our it's not in
the United States national interests to
have a war between North and South Korea
it's just not we trade South Korea we
like South Korea they're you know
they're a bulwark against potential
giant against China which is the next
potential great power threat to the
United States I mean it's not in our
interest to see a war between North and
South Korea
so if you are a Caitlyn Johnstone type
you might say well that's too bad like
so what if North Korea and South Korea
good war and to me that's like well
that's it's just one it's clearly not in
our national interest we'll have that
happen but to it's also kind of
appalling to just be indifferent to that
outcome from a from a human perspective
right like and that's what I mean by
that's the potential for nationalism to
go too far where you say I simply do not
care about what happens to people in
other countries right and that can't be
right because like again if we're
talking about concentric circles of care
there still is some amount of care that
you some duty of some ethical amount of
duty that you owe to people who aren't
citizens of your country and one of them
has probably not be utterly indifferent
to whether or not they go to war and die
yeah but there is it there is a line
that we have to draw because obviously
we're not trying to get involved in
every manatorian issue around the world
so it is it's not really that code of
ethics that's our duty that's motivating
us it's it's money right sure I mean
they're you know much of that is
certainly national interest but again
it's just a question of part I think
it's a question of prioritization like
the globalists would say that this kind
of prioritization is immoral like
Emmanuel macron just said that he just
said it's immoral to prioritize the
interests of your own citizens over the
citizens of other countries so what is
his prioritization system then it's the
one at least having a 20 percent
approval that's that's the that's the
question for me it's like if you're
gonna replace this system of
prioritizing yourself in your community
than your nation first with the
interests of people globally well now
you've got an even bigger pool of
competing priorities that you're gonna
need to start to prioritize and how the
hell what what is the system for
prioritizing the demands needs crisis
ease whatever of seven are we up to 7
billion I feel like we all just
exaggerated the number it was like 5
billion yesterday 6 billion today 7 bill
today whatever but all those good I mean
it's not growing that fast is it but
like seven billion seems to be the
accepted number these days doesn't it
but you know how do you begin to
prioritize that kind of stuff and by the
way like whose money are you gonna be
using to do all that with oh you can use
my money right you use my money in this
nation in this nation-state through our
taxes and such - what dude the all
sudden prioritize other people around
the world now how much of this is really
rhetoric and how much of it is actually
real like on the ground terms of policy
you know I think we've made an argument
here that things that look globalist or
I could actually be nationalist in terms
of really just defending our national
interests it just happens to be that it
includes building a global structure to
you know monitor and control trade or
you know building a system of laws and
treaties that are going to enable
functioning shipping lanes and and
whatnot these these are these are the
items that people include in the sort of
globalist agenda right these
transnational organizations and-and-and
multi multi-party agreements and force
projection and militarily and whatnot
but how much of it is really serving a
globalist goal versus serving a
nationalistic goal and I wonder like
what policy Marcone would implement that
would be different you know if he if he
had versus Trump let's say or just
versus the Nationalists let's say like
how much of this is just dick
waving and saber rattling and whatever
then an actual real-life difference on
the ground in terms of policy I mean one
example is I think Obama though you're
the web registry institution like we
controlled I don't know oh yeah I can I
can't right we controlled that right and
then we gave it to the UN why I don't
know right right for from a nationalist
perspective that doesn't make any sense
right our national interest is best
served by controlling this thing all
right why would we not want to a
globalist recession would say well we
don't have a moral right to own it like
it belongs to humanity
it's like but no actually we we do own
it though and we don't have to give it
up and our national interest is not
served by giving up right
the the globalists logic is the only one
that could say we have an ethical duty
to humanity to give up things to
humanity it's like no our interest come
first were nationalists mm-hmm you know
like we have an ethical duty to consider
people in other countries and we too to
not rent they're not an ethical zero but
their interests do not come before ours
choose the option that has the the
fewest least consequences right on like
do what reminds me Jack of what you used
to say doing what I want while doing the
most good right yeah make us most make
as much money as I can walk while doing
as much good as I can the same time
right yeah well this brings up another
conversation that I had again the guy's
name is escaping me but his name's Alex
and he is the the head immigration guy
Cato I think nono rasca a Rasta yeah and
to his credit he's been really cool in
terms of engagement on Twitter I've
reached out to him a number of times to
have these conversations on immigration
he is a completely wide open no fences
like no no border no passport control
like come one come on early immigration
control is unconstitutional like I won't
and immoral yeah that's the argument
that he would make I think right and
he's been really cool in terms of
engaging with me on that and I what I
what I'm struggling with is trying to
create like a mental model of the world
that where your morality for like your
fellow man like does it extend globally
or does it like is there an actual end
to it because sometimes sometimes your
self interests you know are gonna
compete with other people's
self-interest and you know how how do we
square like being good people and with
you know your the border of your nation
being the end of your morality is that
if that makes I guess I'm having a
little trouble explaining this concept
but you know if you believe that like
the United States is a great economic
driver and a way to bring people out of
poverty in a place for a great
opportunity then I think that there can
be a pretty solid argument made that you
like hey you know if you want to make
your life better come to United States
cuz it will it will expand human
happiness and and and reduce human
suffering but at the same time you know
we have to also focus on our own our own
priorities here at home and to what
extent that that's going to impact us so
I think that's the trade-off I'm
thinking us like I can help these people
in this other country by a giving the
money having them come to United States
and work here whatnot but it all comes
at a cost and I'm trying to figure out
how to square those costs and in the
same sort of moral framework that you
apply to your neighbors and to your
family and to people living in your
community are we supposed to or expect
it to apply that same moral framework to
people that live outside of our country
and then how do we do that and if we do
do that do we have do we even have a
nation like what what is really dividing
us as a nation state versus other people
aside from obviously the Constitution
and whatever living United States but
but Wow like how does that impact our
moral systems it's I think so what
divides us there's a number of different
questions in that that come what divides
us to start there is you know language
culture you know common history common
myths common understanding and common
loyalty to whatever that you know all
those things that we can rightly expect
people within the country to be more
likely to have and that's why you know
when we go you know feel like you're in
that different country when you go to
Albuquerque for Seattle I mean it's
different than DC but it's still America
like you same restaurants same language
same concerns we're all in the same news
like well that's same news for all the
same news like it's not that different
so because we're all in that boat we
have I think arch each other more you
know more care and concern than we do
people in other countries that we are
potential immigrants but is that is that
unique to the United States those
defining characteristics of what makes
up your nation-state I think even that
perspective sure the American distinctly
American sure I mean that perspective is
distinctly American but in that
perspective is also then part of what
binds us right if you look up the
definition of nationalism one phrase
that comes up is the idea of a national
consciousness so I think that idea
that you know you go to Alburquerque or
Seattle and you know you're in America
right because we all kind of share this
unspoken unconscious feeling together
and you can go to France you can go to
and you can go to any other country and
they there's a similar feeling right if
you are an outsider because they all
share this one kind of national
consciousness yeah you know when you're
an expat you know when you're not an
extra as an American like that's a
really powerful difference yeah when
you're in a foreign country like you're
just not you're you're not part of it
right and that's and that's not
ethnically driven that oh no the
consciousness right you don't speak the
language you don't get whatever their
concerns are you don't write because I
mean even go into like Anglo countries I
guess as a white American go to niggle
country and you're like oh yeah this is
this is I am not English I'm not come
here I am NOT you know I may have like
you go to my ancestry of my DNA test and
you'll end up like yes I have a lot of
English DNA but I am NOT English right
right I'm American
so our nationalistic consciousness is is
made up of what shared experience
culture values attitudes you know all
the things I make money in Italy yes
yeah and to what extent are those
malleable and then if you think about
that changing and then you know are like
organizational documents are sort of
fixed depending on your perspective
right hey I wonder you know as as things
shift and change and you know I'm just
trying to understand what people's
perspective of nationalism is and what
the negative critiques are here and this
is sort of from one of those rounds I
think is are the American binds of
nationalism stronger or weaker than
other cases globally that may have
different foundations for their their
binding landing nation so I think I mean
I think we're weaker in terms of the
actual by things that bind 300 million
people together they're gonna be weaker
than a place like Poland you're hungry
right right yeah which has a much more
dramatic history it's like Poland
especially the Red Pony saw their
Independence Day 200,000 people in the
streets of Warsaw's is not a big country
right
there's a very strong nationalistic
feeling in Poland well they have they
have the extra binding component of
ethnic at the I command home at jetan
homogeny thank you imagine aunty
homogeneity three of us we finally I
think the u.s. is stronger and weaker
right one one thing that makes us unique
is that we were kind of one of the first
countries to decide that we are all
going to be bound by principles and
philosophy and a documents and things
like the Enlightenment ideals and not
ethnic heritage right because you can
say that the United States is a country
of immigrants right I know there's a lot
there's a lot in there there is a lot in
there I know so in a way we were like we
were the first we leave pioneers and
this these Enlightenment ideals and I
you know that's what I was always told
growing up right what does it mean to be
American doesn't matter what color you
are it matters that you believe in
freedom and democracy and free speech
and all these things I think that's like
the very defining characteristic like
civic nationalism right right right but
at the same time you you go to Poland
I've been to Poland and I was in awe of
this feeling that they have of their
nationalism and how they are so United
and they're united very specifically in
like deep cultural heritage history for
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
years whereas we've only been a nation
you know for 300 years mm-hmm they've
only been a nation well technically yeah
yeah I mean I get you know your your
point is well again that they've they've
got this very deep strong feeling on the
other hand we have 200 million people on
earth global superpower right right and
you know trying to unify 300 million
people around the chef because around a
shared you know that level of like
especially something like shared
ethnicity I mean impossible you know the
United States was multi-ethnic from
founding and it's a core part of the
history that binds us together is things
like the Civil War fought to liberate
the slaves World War two the Civil
Rights Act and the civil rights struggle
right like these things are if history
is what unites a people or a big part of
it then you can't create an ethnos State
in the United States that would be in
any sense American right that would
connect to any of that type of American
nationalism unless you skipped three
hundred years
of history I started like yesterday my
back like pre founding that's right
right so this is dry this is getting me
to the point that I was trying to you
know on on elitist to which is we lack
the pleura ethnic racial you you not
unification and the American
consciousness and our founding documents
but our this consciousness that you
spoke of is what really defines what it
means to be an American so to what
extent does that consciousness require
handling to what extent does that
consciousness require some level of care
and application and intentionality and
you know proactive engagement with it
how do we foster it can we can we guide
at certain places is that it has that
happened in history is that is that
problematic is it something that we just
leave to evolve on its own or is it
something that we need to be cognizant
of and conscious of and and something
that we need to to really put our hands
on to sort of control because it is
ethereal mm-hmm and it could go away
right yeah and you kind of feel it going
away okay I think it's something that's
been fostered in the past I mean you
look at pictures and images and
traditions and you you missed school to
go to parades right to celebrate your
country you said the Pledge of
Allegiance every single day in school
and remember that we were told that
America was the best country and we're
so lucky to be here and now if you were
to tell your child that or a teacher in
a public school were to say that America
is the best country and we should all be
so grateful to be here I mean they would
lose their job yeah that would be
blasphemous you know what kind of
handling do you have to put on something
like this well I mean I think you have
to do significant product effective
propaganda work on behalf of like
American nationalism because if you
don't it's not it's not like an ethnic
nationalism that just it's just sort of
entrenched in the place right like if if
you're in an ethnically homogenous place
you know the extent to which you all
feel bound or unified together is
probably a lot more robust than if it's
you know
you are members of different cultural
tribes but unified by the civic
commitment so would you say that the the
binds are weaker I'd say that the binds
are weaker binding Americans together
than binding poles together for instance
I think that's it's just hard not to
look at Poland oh yeah I think the
opposite
that said Poland is at a disadvantage
because it can only be poles right like
they can't they can't just form a you
know try to make a European super-state
to compete a great power level with the
United States and with China and what
the Russia they can't doesn't work you
know like they're they're desperately
trying and it doesn't work because they
don't don't have the same national
history or national identity and as a
result they are limited to having strong
nationalisms within very small
geographic places whereas because our
nationalism is inherently more flexible
it's inherently more tolerant we can
integrate a lot more people easily and
it also means we have an advantage when
it comes to integrating new talent right
like say we want to we want access to
the best entrepreneurs in the world the
best technologists in the world well
English is the lingua franca America as
a history of accepting immigrants and
making it easy for immigrants to become
American when they get here so there's
real power and now there's a big
national interest in making American
nationalism accessible that said it's
not just you snap your fingers you
become an American I mean if you if
somebody comes here as Omaha be a
committed wahat believer in Wahhabi
Islam in what sense are they
meaningfully becoming American by moving
here if they if their fundamental
ideology conflicts with everything
anything that would be a unifying
American ideal yeah and is that is that
not a fatal flaw of an open system they
it can and will attract and permit those
in its myths that are actively working
against them or fatally oriented I think
it's a flaw I just don't necessarily
think it's fatal right it's the downside
of being tolerant is that sometimes you
tolerate things you shouldn't and I mean
on net we're better off in a world where
we have a lot of tolerance and
occasionally tolerate too much I think
like you know and as a result you know
I'm Pro integration restriction but also
prima Gration like
it's really really important to American
national interests to continue to bring
in talented top-level people regardless
of you know Creed I remember I got in
trouble for writing something about we
need to I wouldn't I say we need to give
like thoughtful control immigration
control but then we need to embark on
like a 20-year propaganda program of
like America together or we are America
America first or something and someone
when when I got during my like Daxing in
this time when the media was paying
attention to like old words that I had
written people dug that up and said that
that was like this guy's just he's like
a straight-up fascist like saying I was
a fascist because I thought that the
government should work to build an
American consciousness was deemed
fascism now I can see if your goal is to
build this American consciousness and to
you know one that supports the state at
all costs and then you know it exports
hate and violence and starts invading
other countries and whatnot but to say
that any effort towards building a
national identity is is a fascist
tendency I think is really gonna limit
us and it seems to me that one of our
political parties today is anti-american
consciousness and you know I think
Hillary Clinton's campaign in the way
that she adopted and I'm bringing in
another subject real quick here but the
way she adopted the language of
intersectionality and radical feminism
and all these concepts that are an
anthem to Western civilization and the
primacy of the individual I don't know
why she wanted to become president like
why would you want to become president
of the United States the leader of
Western civilization when your faction
members of your coalition members of
your faction members of the party are
actually anti Western civilization and
anti America why I don't I don't get
that do you understand that I mean for
Hillary Clinton it's just power right
like if you're trying to understand
Hillary Clinton's motivations right
that's pretty simple she wants power I
was giving her a little bit more
yes she deserved there that mean the
general problem of I think the left not
having a unifying ideology for the
country I mean other than sort of
unifying against white people in my
judgment like I don't yeah you know
white men white men right like I call
the Democratic Party institutionally
bigoted now cuz I don't want to use
institutionally racist because the
debate about whether or not they're
racist I want to avoid it all right
because they stole the word racism away
from being actually prejudiced and
acting on those prejudices and now
they've incorporated you have to have
this sense of power right exactly so I
sidestepped at a that debate because
they haven't redefined bigotry yet and
they certainly are bigoted certainly
bigoted and not only not only the the
Democratic Party but then the
institution's support the Democratic
Party things that we call the blue
church right the entertainment media
commercial marketing complex to where
there are open bigots on the editorial
board at the New York Times that us in
all seriousness of have said blanket
statements about trying to induce crime
and terror basically against white white
men in particular and the open
institutional bigotry as you described
it I mean it's it's like not even hidden
anymore it's not right obscurity oh it's
celebrated it's a way it's a way to gain
status amongst amongst their peers so
you people have asked me in like a mas
and on questions like do you think
there's gonna be a civil war and you
know we're clearly in a cold Civil War
all right right and like I'm a casualty
you know red hen as a casualty by virtue
of living with me my children are
casualties by virtue of being in my
household because of the way that things
went down but is there gonna be a hot
Civil War I don't know but this idea
that there's enemies in our midst I mean
open bigotry institutionalized bigotry
and open criticism of the concept of
what it means to be an American or
America or the American experiment or
the American consciousness that's
already here and it's already sort of
tearing us apart yeah I mean and to me
that's sort of like what
the big ideological project for the
right it's to defeat that right it's to
say that doesn't get to win we you know
institutional bigotry against a portion
a major portion of our population isn't
okay right we don't think racism is okay
well this isn't okay either right I mean
yes racism was a more profound evil
especially at the time it was right but
that doesn't mean you suddenly that open
institutional bigotry against white
people is okay it's not and it's it's
it's dis unifying one right it's pitting
citizens against other citizens not okay
and it's it's just something that just
doesn't sit right with me personally
right right like the you know the I ya
know it's not just just not okay and so
that's like the Enel you know the
ideological project of the right is what
winning this cold civil war looks like
is defeating the left electoral enough
to the point that they're like hey you
know this intersectionality stuff that
was dumb
we're gonna go back to Bill Clinton and
well yeah being a moderate eating almost
an interpretive yeah right and then back
to like hey maybe we should unify as a
country together around American ideals
it's like once you have that and like
debates about health care or and all the
other stuff that's all just technocracy
that's fine you know however that comes
down America is still gonna be America
at the end of the day but if we lose the
debate about like this major cultural
ideological issue you know big trouble
well I think that the midterm results
showed that that divide is becoming even
more profound you know I think I saw the
voting voting breakdowns from some exit
polls that showed you know something
like 98 percent of black women voted
Democrat and you know 70 some percent of
white women I may have these numbers
wrong but it's it's pretty clear that
the way the the voting is breaking down
across the racial and gender divides Wow
how do how do we how do we stop that
from happening or how do what kind of
conversation do we have with people in
order to you know look I think
polarization inevitably is bad for bad
for us right we don't we don't want one
party to be the party of like minorities
and
but do you say people color and one
party to be the party of white people
yeah that's not good that's not good but
that's in a way that mean I think the
numbers are showing that that's the case
right right and I think part of it is
you know the Republican Party doesn't
have a history of being particularly
woke on on racial issues and in ways
that have given it a lack of credibility
about talking about things like you know
like criminal justice reform even if she
was one Republicans talked about them
like Democrats right we don't feel like
Republicans are meaningfully committed
to those issues right that maybe they've
got any skin in the game on those issues
they'll talk a good game but they're
home oh my god I got skin in the game
they got the you know their private yeah
right that's it yeah so I on the same
tip I have long advocated for the
decriminalization of cannabis in
marijuana from a federal level and I
feel like right now man the Republicans
should be really seizing upon that one
it fits in the libertarian perspective
of low government it fits in a
federalist perspective that they're
gonna argue when they try to challenge
roe v wade right and it's a legitimate
civil liberties issue in that
african-american community gets
incarcerated at a far greater rate for
the same offenses and endures longer
prison sentences for the same offenses
than for white people when it comes to
pot usage and pot distribution so you're
absolutely right that there the
Republican Party doesn't have a great
history here and I think this is this is
a question that I get on the college
tour kids are like how do how do you
know in the Q&A afterwards like 19 year
old kid it's like how do we convince
people that were not racist I mean it's
not tough right it's action not words
right right right which is what I told
them you know like that's people aren't
gonna be convinced by words that you're
not racist they have to like see you in
action and and like realize that you
actually have everybody's best interest
at harder as much as possible and to
some extent you know you can't you can't
perfectly empathize with anybody you're
ultimately constrained by your own
experiences right like to the extent
there's a critique of kind of like this
sort of white witness if you will it's
that like you know you don't you don't
you haven't
all my shoes you can't walk them out my
shoes when you purport to understand my
experience your Foldit you don't write
but that doesn't mean the counter to
that is but yeah I should try though
right I should try to empathize I should
try to like put myself in your shoes I
should try to fully understand what's
going on well what I tried to tell them
was like look this isn't your this isn't
your grandfather's Republican Party
mm-hmm right like we saw the rainbow
flag up on stage oh forget the
Republican convention I've been saying
that a lot I need to double check that
that's right I think that's true you got
Donald Trump saying that the the gay
marriage is settled law mmm and I think
that there's there's a lot of social
issues that have sort of fallen to the
side now because they become settled
like gay marriage has been settled and
that was one thing gay marriage and pot
and like the drug war it was like we're
like two issues that really kept me
solidly on the left for a note for a
long time yeah and once those have been
you know the gay marriage is resolved
and pot decriminalization seems imminent
right it could it could be now it could
be in five years but the trends seem to
be solidly in place that that to me
opened up the ability for me to make a
transition and of course you couple it
with like the craziness
coming out of the Democrats I mean the
Democrats themselves are making it
impossible for a white masculine male to
remain a part of their coalition there's
like absolutely no no self honestly no
self-respecting man white man can be a
Democrat today because the Democrat
Party not only tolerates but supports
and spreads a message of hate and anti
masculinity and anti white guy right I
agree yeah and it sounds crazy to say
that but have there been recent events
or have you always sort of felt like
that or what's driven you to come to
that conclusion because I know what it's
been for me I mean it's just sort like
my lived experience no I mean I have
that I had that lived experience in
college debate where like I was a soul
alone kind of libertarian moderate
conservative around nothing but hyper
liberals and you know there was a time
where it was fine it was really policy
centric debate and we were having
disagreements about health care
and gun reform and so whatever you know
those are just technocratic issues but
at a certain point things changed and
they got to a point where I was
routinely being called racist and
debates without justification
oh no kiddin yeah like in call it like
college college get to her yeah and
these are like you know people who knew
better to look at and I knew what I was
saying and I was being very careful with
it like if you call those things racist
you were just wrong right know saying
things about evolutionary psychology is
not racist right it's just wolf you know
that's a can of worms
yeah like that's one example and also
just sort of a move in debate towards
this I'd just kind of lyin ization of
victimhood and the arguments that were
unbeatable because they were so woke
right like the idea you know topic might
be a policy debate about prosecutorial
authority deferring to get up and say
debate is racist it is anti black here
you know we are standing up against
debate and being anti black is is bad
and and the negative couldn't get up and
say like you shouldn't say that
obviously everybody agrees right that
like racism is bad that shouldn't be
your affirmative thesis that you get to
defend in this debate that's I'm on to
me racism right yeah like that's dumb
long debate there his race isn't bad I
think that's one thing these college
kids are really feeling because
everything is so extreme on a college
campus it's the most extreme and it's
also soakin condensed right it's their
little tiny community and that's what
you live in for four years and just by
being white they're automatically racist
mmm so it doesn't I think a lot of them
feel like it doesn't matter what they do
doesn't matter what they say because
unless they can somehow change the color
of their skin they're always going to be
considered racist yeah and red hen has
seen all this firsthand with me because
she not only supports me at home but
supports me on the road too and so she's
come to each of these events and she
watches and here's the questions and
sees the sincerity of these kids you
know it's just like a 19 year old boy
they all they seem genuinely scared yeah
and overwhelmed I think this huge
feeling of being overwhelmed by the lack
of options and opportunities and and so
here yes you feel like no
cares about them because when you can't
even have a discussion right they at
each event we've had at least two
questions saying how do I talk to
someone on the left right
how do I just have a conversation with
someone who doesn't agree with me and it
is mind blowing that that is a question
that people need help with what the fact
that you just can't even you can't agree
to disagree
because if you disagree with me says
someone on the left and you are a racist
you are a bigot you are sexist
you're a terrible human being right the
left has effectively shut down debate by
saying you know if you just disagree
with us you're you're morally deficient
and Caminada embody embodiment words no
words bad words embodiment thank you of
evil and one of the what are the things
I've seen in kids faces as I give my
talk to them where I talk about in my
book Democrat to the pourable I talk
about the college section where I broke
down the the orientation program at
American University and I and I showed
how the materials and the concepts that
they present say a you're a racist be
you are we don't care about science see
did I go one to see ABC ABC see that
language is manipulate language and
control reality that way through you
know pronouns and other things and and
this is D that the the words that you
say they they're judged by the way
people feel about what you've said
rather than the merit of your statement
and I break that all down and I
explained it in the book and I explained
it in my talks and I see the lights and
the in the eyes of the college cuz
they're just like somebody finally put
it all together for them and has like
helped coalesce this this negative
energy that they're feeling and and put
it into an organized sort of package so
that it all of a sudden they seem to
stop feeling crazy and start to feel
like oh yeah no wonder I'm feeling like
that because this is insane and now
somebody else has told me that it's
insane
and it's really helped me see that it is
and now I don't feel like a terrible
person anymore
right which is all part of the plan
right to make you feel like a terrible
person right it's me yeah it's to push
you in a place where you bend to the
will of this ideology yeah it's classic
manipulation I mean it's it's nothing
but essentially no I don't want to say
brainwashing but no it's a percent I'm
washing it sits under sent brain mind
control and when people say that they're
indoctrination cams colleges these days
they're absolutely right in my research
something like 92% of people that when
Democrats a deplorable said that the
state of affairs on college campuses is
very alarming to them and motivated them
to vote because they had some idea that
Donald Trump was gonna be able to make
influence on the state of affairs on
college campuses now I think that that's
actually happening it's a slow moving
ship he's working on title nine reforms
through the Department of Education
which is a huge thing and we can talk
about later but those kind of things are
gonna take take extended period of time
to shift institutions
I mean if it's even possible yeah I mean
I'm bearish on the possibility of real
meaningful change in the universities I
think they've been totally co-opted by
the most radical faction of the left and
you know I frankly I would just defund
them just aggressively defund them like
I don't understand why the federal
government needs to continue to fund
these places or a rather at least the
departments that aren't hard sciences
right like and maybe history and a few
in a few other disciplines that are like
not hard science but you know have
sufficient rigor but like anything that
ends in Studies can just go away you can
just be defunded y'all y'all can fund it
with your own donations so I you know
somebody who is not necessarily familiar
with you or me will and like the writing
and speaking that we've been doing over
the last few years some somebody could
dip their toe into this conversation and
maybe perceive some of the things we've
talked about as being radical and and
could be all thrown into that basket of
deplorable saw
yes on the right and you know people
will say that just having conversation
around nationalism people will say
having conversation that involves
evolutionary psychology biology people
will say that having a conversation
about race man we must be a bunch of all
writers up here
yeah funny story about that the answer
is no the answer is no yes or is like
both of us have actually like I think
aggressively fought the art right our
own ways and you know we can talk about
like we've succeeded I mean mostly I
think it's they've just committed
seppuku they've made such terrible own
errors no but that would be honorable
yeah right true just giving them too
much credit
right so a display fell down and impaled
themselves yeah just fell down they were
they were not looking and they fell into
a bit of spider down and they could not
get up right and there would be nobody
there standing with the sword to like
chop their head off and spare them the
dishonor absorbing and agonizing no they
actually won a point in laughs is to
know and while they get dragged through
discovery and civil litigation in
Charlottesville just to be clear we are
talking about the alright yeah yes yes
not not Democrats yeah there we go well
yeah we're talking about the alright
Democrats have not committed suicide
that's very different right Democrats
are honorable suicide definitely not now
one of the topics that we had down here
on our list of things to talk about was
it was the death of the hall right and
you know I was just thinking cuz like I
said I want this podcast to be you know
self-critical and open-minded and taking
different perspectives so I was
listening I was listening to things that
we were saying and to somebody who is
not tuned into the definitions that
we're using and has not tuned into sort
of our ongoing discussion and
conversation so basically somebody who's
mildly ignorant and I'll use in a
technical technical way right could you
know swoop in hear this conversation be
like oh my god they're talking about
nationalism they're talking about
propaganda campaigns to make us all
believe we're Americans it sounds like
ethnic erasure and racism and all this
horrible stuff but
you know talk talked a little bit about
your experiences with with alright what
happened to all right where are they
and should we define them should we
should we define them I mean to meet
like the alt-right is an umbrella group
I don't think I think almost nobody
identifies with the name anymore even
the white nationalists are like you
alright the braining is so bad right
which is a bummer because the term
alright and in a vacuum yeah this is a
cool name right it's too bad that they
you know Richard Spencer decided no I
own this cool name and here let me get a
Nazi goop all over alright like
understanding the phenomena of Nazi goop
is actually quite useful right like
these people getting these people get
Nazi goop over things it's pretty bad
the white nationalists won't won't hang
out with you all right now won't hang
out with the nail let's yeah it's just
such a it's such a fine fine line to
walk so yeah so I mean basically I think
the alright has come to mean people that
are very specifically oriented around
some sort of ethnicity or wishing and
this is time back our original
conversation here it wishing that the
binds that held their nation together
were of ethnic origin rather than a
cultural consciousness I think that's
actually the most charitable way anybody
ever defined right right they think I
mean they believe that most real and
central and that essential to national
identity like they reject the
distinction I think between the nation
and the race that makes up the nation
whereas I think that distinction is
exceedingly important and I don't think
also I reject the premise inherent in
that which is the idea that a nation
can't be multi-ethnic right right like I
think America is very clearly a
multi-ethnic nation and a multi-ethnic
country and that an ethnic nationalism
in is America is unamerican right it
doesn't fit into our history and into
our understanding of ourselves well
right and then if you're just gonna like
judge the performance of this American
consciousness on the global scale I mean
how else would you do it besides like
GDP and the military power so like
whatever we have living here in America
remember who's been who members been
here for the last however
200 plus years it's obviously working
right so to say that it's it's
impractical or non-functional or
sub-optimal either on a political skill
on economic skill or even on a
evolutionary scale would be completely
false right so so when people are
talking about ethno States they're
really talking about suboptimal
suboptimal outcomes right no I mean I
mean it would be disastrous Maranon
talking suboptimal I mean the breakup of
the United States and two distinct
ethnic nations would lead to both
internal war and also a collapse of the
world order I mean you know the entire
world order is routed around the United
States as the dominant superpower right
so this nation this notion is
absurd is the end of this yeah it is and
it was from from the get-go another
they're kind of modifying it there their
argument is more well we need to
maintain a white supermajority in the
United States and for me it's like
that's not actually a relevant metric in
my judgment at all right like to me it's
like you know America doesn't stay
America it's going to depend on the
ideology right it's going to depend on
the dominance of particular political
factions it's not going to depend on
whether or not you're counting members
of a particular race and seeing that
they add up to the right number
especially because like just you know
like white people aren't unified at all
at all there are completely different
tribes right but I think what we've seen
though in the voting is that by and
large the minority groups are unified in
their voting and one of the
characteristics a unified unifies them
at least there some of their woke up air
quotes again that's really effective on
a podcast using air quotes or facial
expressions or eye rolls especially is
that you know sort of an opposition to
white power or white head roni hegemony
and that's and that's bad for the
project of American nationalism right
it's a censorship competing ethnic
nationalisms which is it's almost what
that reflects a kind of descent into
competing ethnic nationalism correct
right so I my point and even bringing
this up is that
the Democrat the Democratic Party has in
its coalition people who are ethnically
oriented in their approach to politics
right and so one of the questions I
asked in my book and I think this might
be one of the more dangerous things that
I did bring up is that if people in the
minority parties are gleefully
anticipating in the moment at which they
become a majority voting bloc what is
driving that that Glee and you know what
what does that mean so like you you've
said and I've said and have thought as
well to that like maintaining an right
position which is not our position of
maintaining a white super majority or
majority voting power in the United
States is important and we're saying no
that's not important this idea is an
ideology right because white people
aren't unified but on the on the other
side you there's there's minority groups
that are like can't wait till we have
voting power now is that is that is that
something to you know when is that gonna
happen is there is there a negative
effects to that is that I mean that's
elevating ethnic division to a national
level on a policymaking level right and
so the way I frame it again in terms of
ideology if your ideology is one of
ethnic solidarity and waiting to triumph
over white people then your ideology
needs to be marginalized you know and
moreover like if your political strategy
is to change immigration patterns to to
increase the essentially to like change
change the demographic situation so that
you're going to win your this ethnic
battle it's like no we that can't that's
not okay right and that's not you know
we want to prevent anything like that
from it right of course which is why
which is why I think we both were
talking earlier and and something we've
considered quite a bit which is how do
we how do we strengthen and fortify the
American consciousness in a unified
manner mm-hmm and what does that look
you know these are just rhetorical
questions but like what does that look
like how are we gonna do that moving
forward is it something that's
coordinated on the federal level is it
something that people do philanthropic
lis you know do you do it on Twitter
I mean there's just a ton of like
cultural work to be done about changing
the attitudes of this country and
basically making everybody American
right like and and really putting these
sort of quasi ethnic nationalist
splinter groups making them marginal
right making them toxic making it's like
no that's yes I realize like that's a
powerful driver is like ah we as a
voting bloc love power but that's just
that's just not an American way of
thinking no you're just not and it
doesn't sit with our values no you know
I find it ironic that the very same
people that would criticize others for
having an ethnic perspective or also
then gonna bring sort of ethnicity to
their forefront of their conversation as
well too but yeah that's another
conversation for another day so I think
this is a good place to begin to wrap up
because if anything comes out of this
conversation what I what I want people
to take away from and said it's
important for us to to foster the
American consciousness that it's
important for us to have like a unified
idea of who we are and where we're going
and what we're doing whether its
language culture customs attitudes
expectations norms etc and of course
along the way we're going to have
vigorous and healthy to base when we
don't have the vigorous and healthy
debate when somebody like me gets the
platformed and banned from just having a
regular conversation at a federally
federally funded university you know
with law students with laws particularly
it's not just some college you know
undergrads right and I was looking
forward to talking to the law students
too because I wanted to get deeper into
some federal policy and how it changes
human behavior like the way title 9
stretches all the way into college
relationships and mating and dating
patterns and whatnot because I think
that's fascinating conversation
something I've actually talked a lot
about with Jeffrey Miller on episode
number one so check that out but you
know the walk away from this the
takeaway is that you know American
nationalism is is a good thing to say
that it is inherently evil or Hitler
asked like those those young young
bunnies on CNN 26 years old doesn't know
anything about anything but knows you
know thinks you know
enough to say that being a nationalist
is being a Nazi you know we want to we
want to move away from that type of
rhetoric and and I think that we've had
a good talk here to really talk to dig
into what nationalism means what the
American consciousness is and and the
importance of it and the sort of
unifying evolutionary perspective of
like taking care of yourself first so
that you can then also take care of
people outside of your outside of your
circles and you know I know for me
personally and free will that you know a
strong America can be can benefit the
world through its strengths and and I
think that that's you know that's all of
a sudden sounds super concerned hold
school right like a strong father or
strong family strong neighborhood strong
community then we can help everybody
else and and we lead through strength
and we lead through conviction and we
lead through having a hearty
Constitution and you know that notion is
under attack from all aspects so there's
no surprise to me or to you that the
Marxist globalists you unit union that's
out there that they would all be on one
side and on folks on the other side
advocating a positive masculinity
advocating for a strong family units
advocating for strong communities for
taking care of yourself first so that
then in turn you can worry about
everybody else
you know those dividing lines are pretty
clear and when you lay it out like that
you know it's it's really obvious the
divisions right and and how they seem
they seem to be very very entrenched and
so that's why communication is good and
that's why getting out there and talking
to people is good but that's gonna be it
for this one that's about 90 minutes you
guys have been awesome thank you so much
Red Hen thank you thank you next time
when we're going to have a do an episode
me and Red Hen we're gonna do episode
about relationships so that's gonna be
fun dating and relationships and we'll
thank you very much for coming over and
bring your expertise we didn't even get
to all the items on the list but I think
I think so and it's going to be great
having you know having you on regularly
to talk about current events you know
you've got your debate history so that
makes you a good talker
and and you know I will where can people
find you online and how should they
reach out so I am will Chamberlain on
Twitter and periscope you can that's
basically two places you can find right
now at will Chamberlain spelled CH am
ber laim perfect perfect and Red Hen
what about you you can go to Jack Murphy
lives underscore at red underscore him
on Twitter and not that awful restaurant
that kicked the the press secretary out
of from eating there right some people
were very confused they want you got a
lot of nasty yeah and I am Jack Murphy
and this is the Jack Murphy live podcast
you can find me at Jack Murphy live.com
there's like 80 some essays on there
lots of podcasts and videos go there
check it out while you're there sign up
for my email list if you're watching
this on youtube hit subscribe so that
you get the notification of the new
releases coming out if you're listening
to this on itunes hit subscribe well hit
subscribe everybody hit subscribe and
follow me on twitter at Jack that Jack
Murphy live that's sort of my home base
and that's the best way to get in touch
with me but dm's are always open so
reach out yeah yeah that's what she said
alright guys thank you very much and we
will be back at you pretty soon upcoming
on the podcast is dr. David lay a
clinical psychologist and a sex expert
we're going to talk about pornography
and is it terrible or or what so stay
tuned for that and again thanks
everybody thanks for listening
see you soon